(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T16:37:39.854333",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ゆらゆらり　はらほらり
Swaying gently, fluttering softly
色とりどり　乱れ咲き
Blooming wildly in vibrant colors
花の街　思い出す　この空から
Remembering the city of flowers, from this sky—
こんな出来事から　やってきたこの場所は
The place I've arrived at from such events
はるか遠くにあった　煌びやかな舞台
Is a dazzling stage that once felt so far away
はっとするほど鮮やかな　世界があるんだと知った
I learned there's a world so breathtakingly vivid
あなたの無理難題に　応えてくその度に
Every time I rise to meet your impossible demands,
あっと言わせるような　奇想天外な答え合わせで
With astonishing and out-of-this-world resolutions,
辿り着いたその先に　新しい景色が待っているんだ
A brand new scenery awaits us at the end of the journey
摩訶不思議なミステリー
A deeply mysterious mystery
次から次に起こるたび
Happening one after another,
巧妙なからくりも　暴いてみせましょう
Let's expose even the most clever illusions
どんな難題でも　種や仕掛けはあるんだ
No matter how difficult, there's always a secret and a method,
副作用は気にしない　必ず導き出すから
Don't worry about side effects, I'll definitely lead the way!
あぁ この場所で触れた 人の哀しみや喜びがある
Ah, in this place I touched, there is human sorrow and joy.
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
Every single one of them makes my heart tremble.
はっとしちゃうほど 鮮やかな世界が ここにあるんだ
A world so vivid it takes my breath away is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 応えていく毎日に
In these daily lives where I respond to your impossible demands,
あっと言わせるような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
With astonishing, out-of-this-world answers,
辿り着いたその先に 新しい私が待っているんだ
At the destination I reached, a new me is waiting.
あの頃は 想像もしていない 未来が咲き始めている
A future I couldn't have imagined back then is beginning to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くないかな
Days like this aren't so bad, I suppose.
ゆらゆらり ひらひらり 離れては寄り添って
Swaying, fluttering, drifting apart and drawing close,
そよぐ風に身を任せ 幽夜に舞う
Entrusting ourselves to the gentle breeze, we dance in the dim night.
はーいということで、今日皆さん来てくれてありがとう！
Hiii, so everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
みんな見えてる？見えてますか？
Can everyone see me? Can you see me?
ということで見て！今日はこの新衣装なんですよ！
So look! Today I'm wearing this brand new outfit!
みんな気づいたよね？気づいたよね？さすがに。
You all noticed, right? You noticed, right? Naturally.
はーいということで見てください、このきらびやかな和風の新衣装です！やったー！
Hiii, so please take a look at this gorgeous, Japanese-style new outfit! Yay!
ということでですね、これは今回天女衣装となっております。
So, this time it has become a heavenly maiden outfit.
傘も合わせてみてください、傘ちょっと見えるかな？
Please check out the umbrella as well, can you see the umbrella a bit?
これ見て！夜のね、ちょっと衣装と同じ柄で今回新しく作っていただいたんです！イエーイ！ありがとうございます！
Look at this! It was newly made for this time with the same pattern as the night outfit! Yay! Thank you so much!
はい、ということでこの傘以外にもですね、ちょっとこのあと新しいアイテムもちょっと出てくるのでそちらも要チェックで、というわけで
Yes, so besides this umbrella, some new items will also be coming out later, so be sure to check those out as well.
1曲目は「百花繚乱」を歌っておどらせていただきました！
For the first song, I sang and danced to "Hyakka Ryouran"!
あのね、ちょっとハスのつぼみを使ってちょっと新衣装にチェンジさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？どうだった？
You know, I had it changed into the new outfit using a lotus bud, how was it? How was it?
おおーありがとうありがとう、かわいいですよね？はい、ということで！
Ooh, thank you thank you, it's cute, right? Yes, so!
今回のライブタイトルが「天女繚乱」ということで、
The title of this live stream is "Tennyo Ryouran", so...
ちょっとこの新衣装チェンジとかこれからのゲストの登場とかで
With this new outfit change and the appearance of future guests,
ちょっとね、お花を多く使っているので、花が咲き乱れるという意味を込めて今回この「天女繚乱」というライブ名にさせていただいて、
since we are using a lot of flowers, I named this live "Tennyo Ryouran" with the meaning of flowers blooming in abundance,
見てちょっと、ちょっとね後ろにもチラッとお花が見えたり、ね、夜の衣装にもちょっとお花があったりなんだりしているんですけれども、
look closely, you can see flowers peeking out in the back, and there are flowers on the night outfit too,
はい、ということでこの衣装に合わせて今回もステージ新しく作っていただきました！やったー！
yes, so to match this outfit, a new stage was made for us this time too! Yay!
え、めちゃめちゃ綺麗じゃない？見て、この桜と
Eh, isn't it super pretty? Look, this cherry blossoms and...
この、でっかい月、この、でっかい月とね、この両端にもこっちにもありますけど桜、いやめちゃめちゃ綺麗でしょ！すごいでしょこれ！
This giant moon, this giant moon and, well, there are cherry blossoms on both ends here too, man, isn't it super pretty! Isn't this amazing!
もうめちゃめちゃ考えました！
I thought about it so much!
もうめちゃくちゃね、ちょっと運営さんたちと一緒にお話し合いをしたりとかして、後日実現していただいたり本当ありがとうございます！
I talked a lot with the management staff and we made it happen later, thank you so much!
ということでこの床にもね、ちょっとわかります？気づきました？
So on this floor too, you know, do you get it? Did you notice?
ちょっとね、お花もこの散りばめられていたり、ねの足元にもね、この梅なのかな？このお花をこうね、こうライトみたいな感じで照らしていただいたり
You know, flowers are scattered around, and at the feet as well, are these plums? These flowers are illuminated like lights,
ちょっとね細かくめちゃくちゃ作ってもらってます！ありがとうございます！
they made it so meticulously detailed! Thank you so much!
なんでもうそれも含めてちょっとめちゃめちゃ見ていただきたいなと思っております。
So I hope you'll check all of that out too.
ま、このね、ま、ちょっと、ま、気になってますよね？この衣装、ちょっとみんなで近くで見てもらおうかな？
Well, you're curious about this, right? This outfit, shall I have everyone take a closer look?
じゃあちょっと上から、いいですかカメラさん？あ、ありがとうございます！
So from above, is that okay, camera person? Ah, thank you!
あ、このね、気づきました？この、もう髪型からもうちょっといつもと違うんですよ、
Ah, this, did you notice? This, even my hairstyle is a bit different from usual,
ちょっとお団子、まあいつものちょっと3D衣装の雰囲気も残しつつ、残しつつね、ちょっと新しい髪型にさせていただきました！
with hair buns—while keeping the vibe of my usual 3D outfit, while keeping that, I was able to have a new hairstyle!
そしてそして、ちょっと、ちょっといいですか？あ、あら、あら可愛いですよね！
And and, wait, is that okay? Ah, oh, oh it's cute, right?
あららららららららら
Oh my, oh my, oh my!
このお花、そう、ステージの各所にも入っている
These flowers—yeah, they're all over the stage—
このね、梅っぽい花っぽい感じも入れていただきつつこの、見て！
giving off this plum-like, flower-like vibe, and look!
見ててください。あ、この
Check this out. Oh, and
この振袖にもちゃんと付いてます、このお花。
this long sleeve has it too, this flower.
綺麗でしょ？見て、綺麗でしょ？
Isn't it pretty? Look, isn't it pretty?
よ、可愛いよでしょ？いいでしょ？
Isn't it cute? Isn't it good?
はい、ということで、この足元にもちょっと注目していただきたいんですけど
Yeah, so I'd like you to pay attention to my feet too, but
見て！この草履も新しくなりました！
look! These zori sandals are new!
かわいいよね、こそいよね、ちょっと。袖の色と合わせて、こっち側ね、白で、こっち側はちょっと茶色っぽい感じになってます。
Aren't they cute? They match the sleeves—this side is white, and this side is a bit brownish.
そしてね、この衣装のすごいところがね、どんだけ踊ってもですよ、足元見てください。
And the amazing thing about this outfit is, no matter how much I dance, look at my feet.
めっちゃ伸びるんです、これ！すごいでしょう？
They stretch so much, look at that! Isn't that amazing?
これ、すごくない、これ？どんだけやってもめっちゃ伸びるからね。
Isn't this crazy? No matter how much I do it, they stretch so much.
ということで、はい、このネタでした。
So yeah, that was the joke.
はい、じゃあちょっと
Yeah, so...
ま、この新しい衣装にもなりましたし、新しいステージにもなったということで、じゃあちょっと
we've got this new outfit and a new stage, so let's take...
一枚でもね、ちょっとお写真撮りますか。お写真。
a picture or two. A picture!
このせっかくならし、この桜のさ、めっちゃ咲いてるところあるから、ここでちょ、ちょ、ちょと撮ろうよ、撮ろうよ。じゃ、ちょとカメラさん来てください。こっち、こっち、こっち。
Since we're here, let's take some photos where the cherry blossoms are in full bloom. Come on, cameraman, come over here!
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ映える！見て！すごいでしょう、これ！めっちゃ綺麗だよね。このね、桜の色とかもめっちゃ決めました。
Oh, it looks so photogenic! Look! Isn't this amazing? It's so pretty. I really nailed the cherry blossom colors and everything.
めっちゃ、あ、でもね、このライブ中にもめちゃめちゃ変わったりするので、ライティングとかもね、変わったり雰囲気もまた変わるので、それも含めて見てほしいんですけど
And you know, during the live it changes a lot, the lighting and atmosphere change too, so I want you to check that out as well,
ま、ちょっとそれを踏まえてちょっとここで、お写真なんか撮っちゃおうかな。
but keeping that in mind, I think I'll take some photos here.
みんな、みんなスクショいっぱい撮ってくださいね！みんなハッシュタグをつけて、たくさんポストしてね！撮ってる、撮れてる？いい感じ？
Everyone, please take lots of screenshots! Put on the hashtag and post lots of them! Are you taking them? Looking good?
いい感じ行く？じゃ、ちょっと傘なしバージョンもちょっとやってみますか？どう？傘なし、傘なしもちょっと撮れるかしら？
Good to go? Then how about trying a version without the umbrella? How is it? Can we take one without the umbrella?
お、いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？あ、撮れてる？
Oh, isn't this good? Is it capturing?
お、めっちゃ、お、めっちゃいい角度じゃん！うわ、いいね、いいね、いいね。
Oh, what a great angle! Wow, nice, nice, nice.
はい、じゃあ、ちょっとお写真これぐらいにさせていただきまして
Alright, I think I'll wrap up the photos around here,
続きはね、ちょっと細かい衣装やら、ま、ちょっとスクショタイムはちょっと免罪でね、ちょっと予定しとると思うんで
and for the rest, like the detailed outfits and screenshot time, we've planned them out,
ま、そのあともね、ミニライブとかもありますので、そちらもぜひぜひ、チェックしていただければなと思います。
and after that, there's a mini-live, so please be sure to check that out as well!
そして、え、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
And today's hashtag is right here!
え、ハッシュタグナキリヤメ7周年新衣装3Dで、ちょっと長いんですけど、長いんですけど、このたくさん綺麗なこのステージと、よの綺麗な衣装をたくさん、たくさんスクショして、え、一緒にポストしていってください！
Hashtag Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary New Outfit 3D—it's a bit long, but please take lots and lots of screenshots of this gorgeous stage and beautiful outfit, and post them together!
はい、ということで今回は、え、7周年をかねた、え、7周年ってことは
So yeah, this time, commemorating the 7th anniversary—wait, 7th anniversary
え、もう7年やってるんですか？っていう感じなんですけど
means I've been doing this for 7 years already? That kind of feeling,
え、今回はその7周年と、え、新衣装のお披露目を兼ねたライブとなっております。
but this live commemorates both the 7th anniversary and the reveal of the new outfit.
え、これからもね、ゲストもたくさん呼んでいますので楽しみにしていてください。
We've invited lots of guests for the future, so please look forward to it.
なんとなんと、最後には特大サプライズもあるので、え、絶対最後まで見逃さないでね！チャンネルはそのままだよ！頼むね！
And last but not least, there's a huge surprise at the end, so definitely don't miss out until the very end! Stay tuned to the channel! Please!
夢の中でも
Even in dreams,
花が散ってる
flowers are scattering,
ひらひら舞う暗闇に浮かぶ桜
fluttering down, cherry blossoms floating in the darkness.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall onto the water's surface,
君はもう一度咲くのかな
will you bloom once more?
ひらひら ひらら
Fluttering, fluttering down...
桜月夜に宿る
Dwelling in the cherry blossom moonlit night,
いたずらな風 匂いだけ残して
a mischievous wind leaving only its scent behind.
騒ぎ出した
Memories awaken...
記憶浮かび沈んでゆく
floating and sinking away.
思い出の破片が剥がれても
Even as the fragments of memories peel away,
光る鱗で隠すの
I hide them beneath shimmering scales.
まばゆいほどに美しい
It's beautiful to a blinding degree.
ひらひらひらら　きらきらきらら
Hira hira hirara, kira kira kirara.
瞼の裏暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms float in the dark behind my eyelids,
水面に落ちたら君はもう一度咲くのかな
If they fall on the water, will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら会えないのだろうか
If I say goodbye, will we never meet again?
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Only the feelings left unspoken
花びら浮かんだ桜の橋になれ
Become a bridge of cherry blossoms floating with petals.
当たり前の景色が
The scenery that was once so familiar
ひらひらと舞い音もなく消えてく
Flutters away and disappears without a sound.
細い雨に濡れた想いが霞んでゆく
Feelings drenched in fine rain grow hazy.
他の誰かに向けた笑顔見て
Seeing the smile you gave to someone else,
忘れた日は蘇る
The days I forgot revive.
色のない夜を染めてく
Dyeing the colorless night.
君と出合った去年の春と同じ場所で同じ景色見つめてた
In the same place and scenery where I met you last spring,
咲き誇るほどに痛む
It aches the more they bloom in pride.
君がいない桜生まれ変わってまた咲くのだろうか
Sakura without you—will they be reborn and bloom again?
戻れない場所と知りながら
Knowing it's a place I cannot return to,
散りゆく花びら手のひらのせて
I place the scattering petals on my palm.
花明かりに誘われて胸の中に降り積もる
Lured by the flower's glow, they pile up in my heart.
光と影舞い散る吹雪の思い出だけ白く染めてく
Dyeing only the blizzard's memories of light and shadow white.
ひらひらひらら　きらきらきらら
Hira hira hirara, kira kira kirara.
瞼の裏暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms float in the dark behind my eyelids.
水面に落ちたら君はもう一度咲くのかな
If they fall on the water, will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら会えないのだろうか
If I say goodbye, will we never meet again?
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Only the feelings left unspoken
花びらに変わっても
Even if they turn into petals—
君と出合った去年の春と同じ場所で同じ景色見つめてた
In the same place and scenery where I met you last spring,
咲き誇るほどに痛む
It aches the more they bloom in pride.
君がいない桜夢の中でも花が散ってゆく
Sakura without you—flowers scatter even in dreams.
暗闇に浮かんだ桜が
The cherry blossoms floating in the dark
水面に落ちたらまた会えるのかな
Will we meet again if they fall on the water?
月明かり昇る刻
As the moonlight rises,
灯る赤提灯
Red lanterns are lit.
祭り囃子の合図
The signal of festival music,
ふわり蝶が誘い出す
Fluttering butterflies entice us.
(ちょいと覗いて見てごらん)
(Take a peek and see what's inside)
迷い込めば抜け出せない
Once you wander in, you can't escape.
月明かり昇る頃
Just as the moonlight rises with a glow
灯る赤提灯
Red lanterns start to light the scene
祭囃子の合図
The music kicking off the festival
ふわり蝶が誘い出す
Fluttering butterflies suddenly entice you
ちょいと覗いて見てごらん
Why don't you take a peek and see what's around
迷い込めば抜け出せない
My only warning is - you'll get lost inside
楽しいことがしたいなら
Tell me if you want to have real fun and laugh
おいでませ極楽浄土
Our doors are open, Gokuraku Jodo
歌え歌え 心のままに
Sing it out, and sing it loud, let your soul be free and proud
アナタの声を さあ聞かせて
Turn it up to the beating sound, let's hear you shout
踊れ踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance away, dance away, let's dance the night away
今宵 共に 乱れ狂い咲き
Come with me, tonight we're all blooming like crazy
美しく咲く花も
Even the brightest flower of 'em all
いつか散りゆくもの
Eventually will come to wither
それならこの一夜を
So then why not make this the night we all
もっと熱く愛したい
Go deeper, love harder, till we see the sun
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Why don't we do something "nice" - it'd be a surprise
これは夢か 幻か
Is this a fantasy? Or is this a dream?
嘘も誠も 無い世界
This is a world where you'll find no truth or lies
ゆきましょう極楽浄土
Let's go together, Gokuraku Jodo
歌え歌え 心のままに
Sing it out, and sing it loud, let your soul be free and proud
乱れる髪 息も気にせず
Let your hair wild, whatever's easy, breathe it all out
踊れ踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance away, dance away, let's dance the night away
今宵 共に 乱れ狂い咲き
Come with me, tonight we're all blooming like crazy
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Why don't we do something "nice" - it'd be a surprise
嘘も誠も 無い世界
This is a world where you'll find no truth or lies
ゆきましょう極楽浄土
Let's go together, Gokuraku Jodo
歌え歌え 心のままに
Sing it out, and sing it loud, let your soul be free and proud
アナタの声を さあ聞かせて
Turn it up to the beating sound, let's hear you shout
踊れ踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance away, dance away, let's dance the night away
今宵 共に 乱れ狂い咲き
Come with me, tonight we're all blooming like crazy
今宵 アナタと狂い咲き
Come with me, you and I'll be blooming like crazy
ちょいと覗いて見てごらん
Why don't you take a peek and see what's around
迷い込めば抜け出せない
My only warning is - you'll get lost inside
楽しいことがしたいなら
Tell me if you want to have real fun and laugh
おいでませ極楽浄土
Our doors are open, Gokuraku Jodo
歌え歌え 心のままに
Sing it out, and sing it loud, let your soul be free and proud
アナタの声を さあ聞かせて
Turn it up to the beating sound, let's hear you shout
踊れ踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance away, dance away, let's dance the night away
今宵 共に 乱れ狂い咲き
Come with me, tonight we're all blooming like crazy
今宵 アナタと狂い咲き
Come with me, you and I'll be blooming like crazy
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱの天気キィ
No matter when, no matter where, the weather's always bad
気になるあの娘の悩みもきっとあるでしょ
If you're worried, I'm sure your worries aren't so bad after all
ざっとで半端な憂鬱なども胸おんなし
Hearts full of gloom can easily be cleared away
あんたの中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
Your mind is all a tangled mess
トンマイヘガイイクジがないまほうていしきイケナイ
No matter when, no matter where, the rules are always strict
いけないいけない事柄なんてないから
There's no such thing as things you shouldn't do
イーアルサンシュジャンケンポンでさあおゆき
One, two, rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
ウーリューチパクデデウンニミサレテクユミヲ
Spinning round and round, let's get carried away
もうハイスピードダマヤマヤマおまちかね
Speeding up even more, oh my, oh my, waiting for you
ハチャでメチャなドラマ派手にドラマ乗るよ
Wild and crazy, it's a dramatic ride!
イーイーのづきゅんアイラブユー四六時中愛をちょだい
E-E-Enchanted, I love you, twenty-four seven, will you be mine?
1/2じゃもの足りない
One, two, never enough!
逃げても結局見えないアイツの胸の内を
Even if you run, you still can't see his true feelings
お邪魔の背伸びも機嫌もいらないからさ
You don't need awkward tiptoeing or forced moods
先輩後輩ヤンキージャンキー関係ないし
Senior or junior, yankee or junkie, none of that matters
いざ事情に勝負
Let's settle it right now
キミもしもその気なら
Hey, if you're feeling up for it,
boy meets girl! 恋の始まりそうならさ
boy meets girl! If love is about to begin,
まだ見ぬわざわざ作り出す極楽
Creating a paradise we haven't seen yet
てばそうスイートだな
Then that's so sweet
アレナ、そこが同じだね
Hey, that part is the same, right?
血潮燻で何しようばあでみ
Smoking with blood, what shall we do?
ドラゴンなるよ
Becoming a dragon
意味深なlike you
Meaningful like you
曖昧な愛より直球、遠慮もいわずさあしてちょうだい
A direct pitch over vague love, don't hold back, give it to me
まて、いちびりの手順
Wait, the procedure of a show-off
鼻血ぶーなのだ自分の意思はどんなもんじゃい
Nosebleed-inducing, what's your own will like?
I love you なのだ、白昼中愛をちょうだい
I love you, give me love in broad daylight
捕まえちゃう、愛々々愛はローキューに
I'll catch you, love, love, love is in the low-qu
2分の1がもう満杯
1/2 is already full
ほれなんてしてよ、会いたい楽しで
Hey, what's with that face, I want to meet and have fun
毎晩競そ先輩足りないや
Competing every night, senior, it's not enough
風雲絶景、天真爛漫
Stormy scenic view, innocent and carefree
出逢う情念、滅茶苦茶で
Encountering passions, utterly chaotic
せ〜の、いっにーさん、はいっ!
Ready, one, two, three, go!
回レ!雪月花
Spin! Setsugetsuka
これよりご覧いただきますのは
What you are about to see now
カブキ者たちの栄枯盛衰、時代は常に日進月歩で聞いてって頂戴な
is the rise and fall of kabuki performers. Times are ever-progressing, listen up!
一見は勧善懲悪、悪者どもを一刀両断
At a glance, rewarding good and punishing evil, cleaving villains in two
「でもホントにそれだけで楽しいの?」もなんだって問答
"But is it really fun just with that?" That's the eternal question
どこからともなく現れて、すぐどこかへ行っちゃって神出鬼没
Appearing from nowhere and instantly vanishing, elusive
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋、追いかければ東奔西走
Waiting for a chance feels like a thousand years, chasing takes us everywhere
時代は常に千変万化、人の心は複雑怪奇
Times are ever-changing, human hearts are complex and mysterious
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの?」もうどうにも全身創痍
"But are you really serious about that?" Already battered all over
吟味巡り巡って夜の町、キミは合図踊りだす
Savoring and wandering through the night town, you start to dance
迷い一つ無く踊りだす
Dancing without a single hesitation
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ、華麗に花弁散らすように
Spin, spin, spin, spin, like scattering gorgeous petals
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ、髪も振り乱して
Spin, spin, spin, letting your hair fly wild
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と、この歌劇は続く
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, day after, this opera continues
踊れ歌え、一心不乱に回レ、今宵は雪月花
Dance and sing, spin with single-minded devotion, tonight is Setsugetsuka
この世に平穏訪れるの?
Will peace ever visit this world?
野暮天無作法、馳走物望み、千客万覧、疾風怒濤、悠々閑々
Uncouth, yearning for feasts, bustling crowds, tempestuous, leisurely
乗るかそるか一か八か、金が着いたら絶対絶命
Sink or swim, make or break, once money is attached, desperate situation
「でも本タキにそんなこと言ってんの?」もうまさか起死回生
"Are you really saying that?" A miraculous turnaround
吟味巡り巡って夜の町、たどり辿って夜の町
Savoring and wandering through the night town, following the night town
迷い一つ無く踊りだす
Dancing without a single hesitation
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ、華麗に花弁散らすように
Spin, spin, spin, spin, like scattering gorgeous petals
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ、髪も振り乱して
Spin, spin, spin, letting your hair fly wild
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と、この歌劇は続く
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, day after, this opera continues
踊れ歌え、一心不乱に回レ、今宵は雪月花
Dance and sing, spin with single-minded devotion, tonight is Setsugetsuka
ハッハッハッハッハッ
Hahaha...
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for flowers, two for birds,
手打ち鳴らす
clapping our hands together.
風で三つ、鳴呼、月出て四つ
Three for wind, ah, four for the moon,
鳴らす鳴らす
clapping, clapping.
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for flowers, two for birds,
手打ち鳴らす
clapping our hands together.
風で三つ、鳴呼、月出て四つ
Three for wind, ah, four for the moon,
鳴らす鳴らす
clapping, clapping.
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁散らすように
Like scattering petals gracefully,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪を振り乱して
tossing our hair about,
昨日、今日と、明日と明後日と
yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after,
この戯れは続く
this playful game continues.
踊れ！歌え！一切不乱に
Dance! Sing! Without a single distraction,
回レ！今宵は何処の日？
spin! What day is tonight?
水木金？土日月火？
Wed, Thu, Fri? Sat, Sun, Mon, Tue?
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Hahaha...
ラッシャイナ 平は成り
Welcome, peace is established,
時が来た 正しい 夢現夜もすがら
the time has come, a righteous dream all night long,
変わりゆくことに 恐れなし
have no fear of changing things,
のっぴきならないのは ご免
excuse me, but being cornered is unacceptable.
手毬唄うたい 君達が誘う
Singing temari songs, you all invite us,
悪人に後ろ髪 惹かれても進むべきなり
even if pulled back by villains, we must forge ahead.
流行り廃れの憂き世なら 信ずる者はただ、君だけと
If this world is filled with trends, my only belief is in you.
踊れ騒えや 唄え歌え
Dance and make noise, sing and sing,
案ずる事などないのだから
since there is nothing to worry about.
此の世の世は恨めし神 露知らずちゃちゃちゃ
This world is a grudgeful deity, unaware of the dew, chachacha.
おかしさんで笑って愛嬌消えて
Laughing foolishly, charm fading away,
それそれそれそれ
sore sore sore sore!
今を嘆いて昔を懐かしむ
Lamenting the present, longing for the past,
君の心の内側 涙川
inside your heart lies a river of tears.
どこにいても巡る巡る台座に君を連れて
No matter where you are, taking you to the revolving pedestal.
あまりてなどか人ぞ悲しき 身勝手なのが世の理か
Why are humans so sorrowful? Is selfishness the way of the world?
万物普遍 虚像の偶像 俗な答えなどあらずとも
Universal truths, false idols, even without vulgar answers,
僕ら巡りあうこと まさに一期一会
our meeting is truly once-in-a-lifetime.
酸いも甘いも試練 連れ添ってこの手握って
Trials of sweet and sour, staying together, holding this hand,
生きづらい此処、浮き世から 旗を掲げよ 宵闇明く
from this difficult, fleeting world, raise the flag as twilight breaks.
酔い上がりや 照れれば忘らる
Drunk and high, if embarrassed, it's forgotten,
昔も今も変わらず
unchanged from the past to the present.
浮き世 人を投げ可愛し
Fleeting world, throwing people, how cute,
いっそてちゃちゃちゃ
might as well, chachacha.
おかしさんで笑って愛嬌消えて
Laughing foolishly, charm fading away,
それそれそれそれ
sore sore sore sore!
止まる春も いずれ行く雪の日も
Spring that halts, snowy days that eventually pass,
日出づるすべての輝きを君に見よう
let us see all the brilliance of the rising sun in you.
彩ろい色 どこまでも偶然なる晴れを眺めて
Colorful hues, gazing at the endlessly accidental clear skies.
負けて一丸 欲しがる 欲しがる 欲しがる声
Losing as one, crying out for more, more, more voices,
勝って選んで 勝って選んで 泣いて泣いて泣いて
winning and choosing, winning and choosing, crying, crying, crying.
去る者も望まぬ聖地 満ち足りないない
Even departing ones don't desire this holy land, never satisfied.
また進む道だから どんな時も前へ出せ
Since it's a path we walk again, step forward no matter what.
流行り廃れの憂き世なら 信ずる者はただ、君だけと
If this world is filled with trends, my only belief is in you.
踊れ騒えや 唄え歌え 案ずる事などないのだから
Dance and make noise, sing and sing, since there is nothing to worry about.
此の世の世は恨めし神 露知らずちゃちゃちゃ
This world is a grudgeful deity, unaware of the dew, chachacha.
おかしさんで笑って愛嬌消えて
Laughing foolishly, charm fading away,
それそれそれそれ
sore sore sore sore!
今を嘆いて昔を懐かしむ 君の心の内側 涙川
Lamenting the present, longing for the past, inside your heart lies a river of tears.
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても巡る巡る
That won't do, no matter where you are, revolving...
よおおおーっ！！！
Yooooooo!!!
じげむ じげむ ごこうのすりきれ
Jugemu, jugemu, Gokou-no-surikire,
かいじゃりすいぎょの すいぎょまつ うんらいまつ ふうらいまつ
Kaijarisuigyo-no, Suigyoumatsu, Unraimatsu, Fuuraimatsu,
くうねるところに すむところに やぶらこうじの ぶらこうじ
Kuuneru-tokoro-ni, Sumutokoro-ni, Yaburakouji-no, Burakouji,
ぱいぽ ぱいぽ ぱいぽのしゅーりんがん
Paipo, Paipo, Paipo-no-shuuringan,
しゅーりんがんのぐーりんだい
Shuuringan-no, Guurindai,
ぐーりんだいのだいぽんぽぴーの ぽんぽこなの ちょうきゅうめいのちょうすけ！
Guurindai-no, Ponpokopi-no, Ponpokona-no, Choukyuumei-no, Chousuke!
ちょいとお時間いただきます
Let me have a bit of your time.
ご清聴ください 整いました！
Please listen carefully, we're ready!
笑うこととかけまして (はっ！)
You write it "laughing" (Ha!)
お祭り野郎とときます (そいや！)
You read it "let's party" (Soiya!)
そのこころは？ そのこころは？
And the point of that is, and the point of that is...
どちらもハッピ(法被)になるでしょう
That everyone will be happy!
おあとがよろしいようで
Thank you kindly for your attention.
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh,
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Life may be hard, but let's laugh,
笑おう(ソイヤ ソイヤ) 泣いたら負けだ
Laugh~ (Yeah! Yeah!) If you cry, you lose!
やけくそ笑いましょう
So just laugh until your sides ache!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Life may have its ups and downs,
乗り越えたあっぱれ日本人
But the great Japanese can get over it,
笑おう どんな時でも
Laugh! Whatever time may bring,
ナニクソ笑いましょう
laugh until you run out of breath.
ぐわはは(ぐわはは) にょほほ(にょほほ)
Ha ha ha~ Ha ha ha~ / Bwa ha ha~ Bwa ha ha~
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Who cares where you are? Just laugh,
笑顔(笑顔!) 笑顔(笑顔!)
Smile~ (Smile~) Smile~ (Smile~)
笑う門には福来る！
Smile and the world will smile back at you!
皆様、本日はようこそおいでいただきました
Welcome everyone, thank you for coming today,
ここで一席！！
And for this seat!
ねずみの娘がお嫁に行って、じきに帰ってきたんで
A mouse's daughter was married off, but came back immediately,
ねずみのおかあさんが大変怒って、
And the mouse's mother was very angry,
「あんな、いいところへ、おまえ嫁いで誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？」
"You were married off to such a nice place, Who did you dislike to have come out?"
「いいえ、誰もしゃないですけれどご隠居さんがやさしんでいやなの」
"No, it's not that I disliked anyone, It's just that the retired old lady is too kind, that's why I dislike it."
「やさしいんなら結構じゃないかね」
"If she's kind, isn't that pretty good?"
「でもねこんなねごい声すもの」
"But, she speaks with a cat's purring voice."
忙しさに身を任せて 消えていくだなんて
To just leave it to being busy, And vanish away, how ridiculous!
消えていくだなんて べらんめぇ！
how ridiculous!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても
Laugh, laugh, even if you can't laugh,
笑うしかないでしょ 笑いましょう
You have no choice but to laugh, let's laugh,
笑おう(ソイヤ ソイヤ) 口角上げて
Laugh~ (Yeah! Yeah!) Raise the corners of your mouth,
ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's just laugh,
応仁の乱 大飢饉さえ
Even the Onin War and the Great Famine,
クリアして現代日本人
The modern Japanese have cleared it all,
笑おう 未来永劫
Laugh, forever and ever,
ぐわはと笑いましょう
Let's laugh with a "Guhaha!"
小娘のたわごとなんて 切り捨てないで
Don't just brush it off as a young girl's idle chatter,
しかめっつらなんか変な顔 笑顔を見たいから
Making a sour face is a strange face, Because I want to see your smile,
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh,
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Life may be hard, but let's laugh,
笑おう(ソイヤ ソイヤ) 泣いたら負けだ
Laugh~ (Yeah! Yeah!) If you cry, you lose!
やけくそ笑いましょう
So just laugh until your sides ache!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Life may have its ups and downs,
乗り越えたあっぱれ日本人
But the great Japanese can get over it,
笑おう どんな時でも
Laugh! Whatever time may bring,
ナニクソ笑いましょう
laugh until you run out of breath.
ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's just laugh,
ぐわはは(ぐわはは) にょほほ(にょほほ)
Ha ha ha~ Ha ha ha~ / Bwa ha ha~ Bwa ha ha~
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Who cares where you are? Just laugh,
笑顔(笑顔!) 笑顔(笑顔!)
Smile~ (Smile~) Smile~ (Smile~)
死んでも夢を叶えたい？
"Want to fulfill my dream even if I die?"
いや、死んでも夢は叶えられない
No, dreams cannot be fulfilled even in death.
それは絶望？ それとも希望？
Is that despair? Or is it hope?
過酷な運命乗り越えて 役がなくても突き進む
Overriding harsh fates, pressing forward with no role—
それが私たちのサガだから！
Because that is our Saga!
誰が弔う
Who mourns?
死地は彼方
The land of the dead is far away.
静寂を破り 芽吹いた夢を
Breaking the silence, the budding dream—
誓え 穿て
Make a vow, pierce through!
重なる 屍高みへ 届くまで
To the heights of the overlapping corpses, until I reach—
吼えろ 徒花
Roar, Adabana!
朽ち果てても進め
Even if I rot away, I will advance.
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
I won't let it be taken by the mockery of dignity.
飢餓を解き放て
Unleash the hunger!
枯れても走る ことを命と呼べ
Call it life to run even if I'm withered.
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Shout to the sky, the definition of survival.
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let me cut my bones and sever the darkness!
雲間に光る 簒奪の勝機
In the clouds, the winning opportunity of usurpation shines.
覚悟を宿命に突きつけて
Stake your resolve on destiny!
天下に狂い咲く サガ
Blooming wildly in the world, Saga—
SAGA
傷ひとつ無い 手など愚か
The hands that have no wounds are foolish.
意思も自由も その身を投げて 守れ
Throw your body, throwing away both will and freedom—protect!
退くな 涙も血も無い 神話を築くまで
Do not retreat, until we build a myth with no tears or blood.
燃えろ 修羅花
Burn, Shurabana!
鼓動亡き世界で
In a world without a heartbeat,
摂理に抗い 天命も無礼に
Resisting providence, even being rude to heaven.
腐鎖切り抜けて
Cut through the chains of corruption!
心を無くすことが死と知れ
Know that losing your heart is death.
極めど儚い 偶童の寵児
A transient idol, a favorite child.
目には目を剥き 牙を剥け
Turn eye for eye, and bare your fangs!
いつか誰もが 散華する捨て石
Someday everyone is a sacrificial stone that falls.
輝け 刹那無限の火花
Shine, the sparks of fleeting infinity!
乱世に奔る
Running through the turbulent world—
SAGA SAGA SAGA
何が神の冒瀆か さばきなどさせない
What is a blasphemy against God? I won't let you judge me!
希望高らかに打ち鳴らせ
Ring out the hope high and clear!
呼吸よりも生きた証
Proof of life, more than breathing.
吼えろ 徒花
Roar, Adabana!
朽ち果てても進め
Even if I rot away, I will advance.
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
I won't let it be taken by the mockery of dignity.
飢餓を解き放て
Unleash the hunger!
枯れても走る ことを命と呼べ
Call it life to run even if I'm withered.
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Shout to the sky, the definition of survival.
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let me cut my bones and sever the darkness!
雲間に光る 簒奪の勝機
In the clouds, the winning opportunity of usurpation shines.
覚悟を宿命に突きつけて
Stake your resolve on destiny!
荒野を駆ける 乱世に挑む
Running through the wilderness, challenging the turbulent world.
天下に狂い咲く サガ
Blooming wildly in the world, Saga—
SAGA SAGA
寄り添う二人に 君がオーバーラップ
Your image overlaps with the cuddling couple
色なき風に 思い馳せて
And the passing wind makes me think
触れた手の温もり 今も
I remember the warmth of your hand even now...
Stop Stop Stop Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, stop, stop, stop the time
そう いつの一日だって
Yes, no matter what day it is
君の言葉 忘れないの
I won't be able to forget your words
会いたい時に 会えない 会いたい時に 会えない
When I want to see you, I can't. When I want to see you, I can't.
切なくて もどかしい
It hurts and I'm frustrated
から紅に 染まる渡月橋
Togetsukyou dyed in crimson red
導かれる日 願って
Praying for the day I'll be guided
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも こころ 君のそば
Always, my heart is by your side
いにしえの景色 変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged
今 この瞳に 映し出す
Reflected in these eyes right now
彩りゆく 季節越えて
Crossing seasons of changing colors
覚えていますか
Do you remember?
ねぇ いつになったら また巡り会えるのかな
Hey, when will we be able to meet again?
会いたい時に 会えない 会いたい時に 会えない
When I want to see you, I can't. When I want to see you, I can't.
この胸を 焦がすの
It scorches this heart of mine
から紅に 水くくる時 君との想いつなげて
When water ripples in crimson red, connecting my thoughts with you
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を探してる
Always searching for you
君となら 不安さえ どんな時も消えていくよ
With you, even anxiety disappears at any time
いつになったら 優しい 抱きしめられるのかな
When will I be held gently in your arms?
から紅の 紅葉達さえ 熱い想いを告げては
Even the crimson autumn leaves tell of their burning feelings
ゆらり 揺れて 歌っています
Swaying gently, I am singing
I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想う
Always, always thinking of you
はい、というわけでここまでどうでしたでしょうか！
Yes, so how was it up to this point?!
いやもう数多くのゲストに出ていただいて、もう今日は本当に嬉しいです。
Man, we had so many guests appear, I'm really happy today.
本当に今回はね、ライブは最初にもやったんですけど、ちょっと和風な感じでまとめさせていただいたので、
Really this time, the live started with that too, but we tied it together with a bit of a Japanese style vibe,
曲も、もうほぼほぼ全部和風っぽい感じでちょっと雰囲気をね一つに統一して、今回はライブを作らせていただきました！
and the songs are almost all entirely Japanese-style, unifying the atmosphere into one, so we made this live performance!
そして、みんな気づいたかな？ちょっと歌ってる最中、ちょっと気づきました、これ？
And did everyone notice? During the song, did you notice this?
おっ、気づきました！新しいマイクなんですよ！
Oh, you noticed! It's a new microphone!
すごいですよ、すごいし。え、めっちゃ見て、このちょっと、この…
It's amazing, it's amazing. Eh, look closely at this, this...
ちょっとおそろいなんですよ。
It's a matching set.
ちょっとこっちもね、ほら、見えるかな？
Look here too, can you see?
見える？ほら！
Can you see? Look!
え、めちゃくちゃ可愛いですよこれ！
Ah, it's super cute, isn't it?!
イエーイ！これ新しいマイク、
Yay! This is the new mic—
あ、ここもね、飾りもついてるんですよ、この鈴と、この紐もねついてて可愛いでしょう！
Oh, and see, there are decorations here too, with this bell and string attached, isn't it cute?!
はい！これもねお揃いです。やったー！
Yes! This is also matching. Yay!
はい、ということで、え、今回ですね、まだサプライズが残っております。
Right, so, um, this time, there are still surprises remaining.
ですが、え、その前にちょっと告知をさせていただこうかなと思います。
However, um, before that, I'd like to make a little announcement.
それでは、告知……どどん！
Well then, the announcement... ta-da!
百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズ！イエーイ！
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Goods! Yay!
はい、えーと、いうことで、最初は……こちら！
Right, um, so first is... this!
卓上屏風です！めちゃくちゃ可愛いでしょう、すごいでしょ！
It's a desktop folding screen! Isn't it super cute, isn't it amazing?!
えーと、デスクに立てて飾れるサイズの屏風となっております。
Um, it's a folding screen sized to stand and display on your desk.
こちらはですね、ガビラン先生の描き下ろしのものと本日来ている新衣装と同じです。
This features newly drawn art by Gabiran-sensei, the same as the new outfit I'm wearing today.
同じ屏風をねちょっと飾ってくださいねみんな！
Everyone, please display this matching folding screen!
はい、え、可愛いでしょう！このねステージも背景のステージもちょっとそれっぽい感じに合わせいただきました。可愛い！
Yes, um, isn't it cute?! The stage and background stage were matched to look just like it. Cute!
続いて、こちら！
Next is this!
湯呑みとなっております。
It's a tea cup.
え、こちらはですね、三川あゆむ先生に描き下ろしていただいた、ぽよよに引っかかったですね、今回もこちらの新衣装での、え、のったよのがミニキャラで描かれた湯呑みとなっております。可愛いでしょう、
This is a tea cup with newly drawn art by Mikawa Ayumu-sensei, featuring mini characters of Poyoyo and me in the new outfit! Isn't it cute?
こうやって、こうやって乗ってます、乗ってます！可愛いでしょう。
Like this, sitting right on top! Isn't it cute?
そして、続いてこちら！こちら扇子となっております。
And next is this! This is a folding fan.
こちらはですね、気づきますか？こちらもそうです、新衣装と同じ柄の、え、扇子となっております。
This one—have you noticed? This is also a folding fan with the same pattern as the new outfit!
ちょっとね、ど真ん中に「余」って入ってるんですけど、こちら、入れるかすごい迷いました。
It has "Yo" right in the middle. I debated a lot on whether to include this.
これ、入れる、入れようかな？え、どうしようかなって、おみさんとちょっと話して、こちらになりました。
Should I include it? What should I do? After talking with Omi-san, this is what we decided on.
ちょっとね、あのこの用の右左で、この、振り袖と同じこっちの色とこっちの色で、ちょっとね、新衣装っぽい感じにさせていただきました。
With the right and left sides of the "Yo", matching the colors of the furisode sleeves, we made it feel very much like the new outfit.
そして、続いてこちら！卓上ライトとなっております。
And next is this! A desktop light.
アンドン風の卓上ライトで、新衣装にこちらもですね、合わせた、え、和風のデザインとなっております。
It's an lantern-style desktop light, designed in a Japanese style matching the new outfit.
ぜひね、飾って、あの和風っぽい風情ある、お部屋タイムをね、過ごしていただきたいなということで、
I hope you'll display it and spend some atmospheric, Japanese-style relaxing time in your room,
可愛いでしょうこれ！いいよね、めっちゃ、おすすめですね、こちら、おすすめです！
Isn't this cute?! It's so nice, I totally recommend this one!
はい、続いてこちら！
Yes, and next is this!
こちらですね、お馴染み、販売ボイス、こちらのタイトルは、
This is the familiar sales voice, and the title is...
「新衣装でデート」ということで、内容は、新衣装のよと水辺で、え？水辺で？で、デートしている内容となっております。
"A Date in the New Outfit". The content is about going on a date with Yo in her new outfit by the waterside—wait, the waterside?!
ま、ステージにもね、ちょっと水辺、あ、後ろにね、ありますけども、はい。
Well, there's a waterside on the stage too, ah, right behind me, yes.
はい、そしてそして、フルセットをご購入の方は、こちらです！
Yes, and furthermore, for those who purchase the full set, here it is!
数量限定バージョンは、直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、え、ガビラン先生描き下ろしポストカードとなっております。可愛い！
The limited quantity version includes a postcard with an autograph & duplicated message, plus a newly drawn postcard by Gabiran-sensei. So cute!
え、通常バージョンは、複製サイン＆メッセージ入りの、え、ガビラン先生描き下ろしポストカードとなっております。
The regular version features Gabiran-sensei's newly drawn postcard with a duplicated sign & message.
さらに、新衣装リスナーに褒めてもらって喜んでいるよの特典ボイスがついてきますね。
Furthermore, it comes with a bonus voice of Yo being happy after being praised for her new outfit by listeners.
タイトル「またデートしようね」ってこれは一体何なんだという感じなんですけど、まね、あの気になった方はぜひ、あの聞いていただければと思います。恥ずかしいのでこのへんにしておきます！
The title is "Let's go on a date again." What on earth is that about? Well, if you're curious, I hope you'll give it a listen. It's embarrassing so I'll leave it at that!
はい、ということで以上、百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズでした！みんな買ったよね？よろしくお願いします！
Right, so that wraps up Nakiri Ayame's 7th Anniversary goods! Everyone bought them, right? Thank you so much!
と、いうことなんですけど、こちら、まだ終わってません！
But having said that, this isn't over yet!
まだチャンネルをそのままで頼む！ということで、まね最初ちょっといった、そろそろまあサプライズをねみんな気になってると思うんで、
Keep your channels tuned! As I mentioned at the beginning, I think everyone's getting curious about the surprise,
ちょっとサプライズに行っちゃおうかなと思います。みんな気になるよね？
so I think we'll move on to the surprise. Everyone's curious, right?
気になる、気になる！
I'm curious, I'm curious!
え、そうですよね！と、その前に、このステージ上へ参ります！
Right, exactly! But before that, let's head up to this stage!
うわ、すごい！上上がってる！海の見えてすごいでしょう！みんな見て！見えてる？見えてる！みんな見て！ステージもよも見て！
Wow, amazing! We're going up! Can you see the ocean, isn't it amazing?! Everyone look! Can you see? I can see! Everyone look! Look at the stage and look at me too!
こちら上に上がってきたんですけども
We've come up here, but...
まぁ上でね、何をするのかと、まぁ、薄々ちょっと気づいてるんじゃないかなと、はあ、
I think you guys have probably already faintly figured out what we're doing up here... haha.
まあ、もうなんですけれども！
Well, of course!
何か分かるかな？
Can anyone guess?
みんな教えて！教えて！教えて！みんななんだと思う？なんだと思う？
Everyone, tell me! What do you guys think it is?
おお、なんか、おお、もちろん！
Oh, like, oh, of course!
ほら私、おお！当たってますね？うんうん、なんと！
Look at me, oh! You got it right? Yeah, and guess what!
はい、こちら、なんとこちらです！どどん！
Yes, here, and here it is! Ta-da!
新曲『花吹雪』でーーす！やったーー！
Our new song, "Hanafubuki"! Yay!
いや、もうだいぶ長くお待たせしたと思うんですけど、待望のオリジナル曲の、新しいのいつだ！みたいなね感じ待っていたかと思うんですけど、
Man, I think you've been waiting for a long time, waiting like "When's the new original song coming out?!"
え、こちら、え、昨日作詞曲ベルさんに書いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
The lyrics and music were written by Vell-san yesterday! Thank you so much!
え、テーマはですね、華麗な歌声かける和風ロック！
The theme is: gorgeous vocals paired with Japanese-style rock!
え、可愛いだけじゃない一味違うオリジナルソングとなっております！
It's an original song that's not just cute, but has a unique flavor!
はい、このね、こうきれいな華麗で、こう重厚な和風ロックとなっておりますので、え、メロディとかね歌詞もこだわり抜いて、え、磨き上げていただいた楽曲となっておりますので、ぜひぜひ皆さん、え、聞いてください！
Yes, it's a beautiful, gorgeous, and heavy Japanese-style rock, with meticulously crafted melody and lyrics, so everyone, please, please listen to it!
え、9月4日0時から、本日の0時からですね、え、各種音楽サイトでリリースされるので、ぜひ聞いてください！
Starting September 4th at midnight—from midnight today—it will be released on various music sites, so please listen!
聞いてるね？いっぱい聞いてるね？
You're listening, right? Listening a lot, right?
はい、それでは皆さん、大変長らくお待たせいたしました！
Yes, so everyone, thank you very much for waiting so long!
え、最後はこの新曲『花吹雪』で、え、お送りさせていただきたいと思います！
Finally, I'd like to perform our new song, "Hanafubuki"!
え、感想などもね、え、この衣装もステージと一緒に、え、ポストしてください！たくさんポストしてねーー！
Please post your impressions, along with this outfit and stage! Post a lot, okay?!
え、最後にはですね、面会パートで、え、ちょっと衣装のおしゃれになったり、詳しい感じのお話をしたり、え、ミニライブもありますので、そちらの方もぜひぜひ見に来てくれたら嬉しいです！
Finally, in the meeting part, we'll talk in detail about the stylish outfit, and there's also a mini-live, so I'd be happy if you came to see that too!
はい、それでは
Yes, so...
聞いてください。花吹雪！
please listen to "Hanafubuki"!
共に散る宿命なら
If our fate is to scatter together,
派手に散りましょう 花吹雪
then let us fall grandly—a storm of blossoms.
花吹雪
A storm of blossoms.
ひらひら舞い落ちる空 とうに散った
Fluttering, falling through the sky—dreams that scattered long ago,
泡沫の夢
bubbles in the wind.
千の花は麗しく咲く
A thousand flowers bloom in breathtaking beauty;
叶う逢瀬は刹那
the encounters we wished for last but a moment.
ふわり艶やかに舞う蝶の儚い命
Softly, gracefully dancing—a butterfly’s fleeting life.
するり堕ちる今宵は何処 甘ず風揺れな
Slipping away, where is tonight? The sweet wind trembles.
狂おしく今咲き誇れ
Now, madly, bloom with pride!
共に散る宿命なら
If our fate is to scatter together,
光満ちた舞台で笑え
then let us laugh upon a stage of brilliant light.
闇を裂く旋律はゆりりと薫る 夢を咲かせましょう 花吹雪
The melody that tears through the darkness sways and perfumes the night. Let our dreams bloom in a storm of blossoms.
くらくら燃ゆるは焰 遠く咲いた明くる日の夢
Dizzying flames burn brightly; dreams of tomorrow blooming in the distance.
正か否か惑わずにいこう 過去の痛みを胸に
Right or wrong, let us go without hesitation, carrying the pain of the past in our hearts.
誰そ彼に祈りをひとつ
In the twilight, a single prayer,
涙の川を穿つ声響く 慎ましくだけ進むだけ
a voice that pierces the river of tears echoes. Modestly, simply, just keep moving forward.
茜さす空の果てに 褪せた過去の憧れを見る
At the end of the crimson-glowing sky, I see the faded longings of the past.
澄み渡る静寂に未来を繋ぐ 答え求むれどにべも無し
In the clear, vast silence, connecting to the future. Seeking an answer, but none is given.
星の降る夜明けまで続く歌よ 彼方へ届け
Until the dawn when stars fall, O endless song, reach across the distance.
湧き上がる情熱が世界を照らす
This passion rising within will set the world alight.
共に散る宿命なら
If our fate is to scatter together,
派手に散りましょう 花吹雪
let us fall grandly — a storm of blossoms.
光満ちた舞台で笑え
laugh upon a stage of brilliant light.
闇を裂く旋律は
The melody that tears through the darkness
ゆらりと薫る
sways, and gently perfumes the night.
夢を咲かせましょう 花吹雪
Let our dreams bloom in a storm of blossoms.